

ABHISHEK RAJ ARYA

COMPUTER SCIENCE FACULTY
NETWORK SYSTEM ENGINEER
LINUX SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR
IT SUPPORT SPECIALIST
GRAPHIC DESIGNER
VIDEO EDITOR

CONTACT

Near Nagar

Parishad, Main road

JEHANABAD, Bihar (804408)

9097723330

techifyarya@gmail.com

LANGUAGE

English Hindi

CERTIFICATION

Advanced Diploma in Computer
Application. (ADCA)
2016

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Work with UNIX/LINUX Systems and Networking Administration and technical support to end-users, leveraging broad-based expertise to handle problem identification, diagnosis, resolution, and escalation via helpdesk system, telephone, and remote support tools. Performed security administration functions in a company for servers, user, data, and remote access.

DUTIES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

- Install the required systems and **security** tools to provide protection.
- Configured and maintained all networking devices, workstations, server hardware, operating systems.
- Ensured the protection, security, and integrity of the company's networks, managed user accounts, file accessibility, and backup recovery.
- Responsible for resolving network issues using network link using Ping, tcptraceroute, traceroute, tcpdump.
 - Installation/Administration of **RHEL 7.9**, **Fedora, Dabian** on Multiple Servers Configuration, testing on both pyhsical and virtual machines.
- Install and server configration of various services like
 DHCP, NFS, DNS, Apache Web Server, Samba, SSH, FTP/
 SFTP, Package Management, File System Management.
- User administration: LDAP, Kerberos
 Maintain organization data with LVM. SSH Server SSH Client

TECHNICAL SKILLS & ABILITIES

- Deep uderstanding of networking: Iptables, Firewall, TCP/IP,
 UDP, DHCP, Postfix, SMTP
- Troubleshooting Network concerns.
- Knowledge of C, PYTHON, CSS, HTML, Q-BASIC, VM-ware NETWORKING, Graphic Design Software.
- Solving any Operating System Problems.
- Familiar with: 'Linux', 'Ubuntu', 'Machintosh apple's
 OS', 'Windows', 'Android'.
- Solving Computer Hardware & Software issues.
- Providing phone and **online support** to users.
- Supporting audio-visual interface with computer workstations and telecommunications technologies.
- Have a very good typing skill.(approx. 70wpm)
- Familiar with : Microsoft Office
- Video & Photo Editor [Photoshop, Premiere Pro]
- Graphic Designing [Adobe Illustrator, Corel Draw]
- Scripting Bash, Python

ONLINE PROFILE



CsEdu4Schools

▶

Arya Click

f

Techify

[Technology News and Updates]

HOBBIES

Teaching
Reading Books
Photography
Travelling

Cooking

Driving

WORK HISTORY

COMPUTER SCIENCE TEACHER, COMPUTER EXPERT, NETWORK ARCHITECT

Mahabodhi Mission School

Computer Science Faculty

01 Feb 2017 - 06 March 2018 Jehanabad, Bihar

Big Byte Pvt.Ltd (A Institute of IT)

IT Trainer & Teacher

2018 - 2019 Jehanabad Bihar

Pradhan Mantri Kaushal Vikash Yojna

Computer Instructor and Trainer

2019 (Jan - May , 2 Session) Patna, Bihar

Pious Mission School +2 level

Computer Science Faculty 05

March 2019 – Till Date Arwal, Bihar

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER APPLICATION

(BCA) Magadh University

JAN 2019

With good degree (76%)

ITERMEDIATE

May 2014

Magadh University

First Division (63%)

MATRICULATION

D.A.V Public school, CBSE Board

Passed - 2012

with 60%